<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-09T09:14:25+00:00</updated><id>https://freedomtour.uk/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Freedom Tour 2021</title><subtitle>The Freedom Tour was a Summer campaign, travelling through the UK, aiming to connect and grow the wider movement for a democratic, ecological and sane society. It aims to achieve this through street canvassing and hosting &quot;Crisis Talk&quot; community events.
The team behind it is currently in reflection after 8 weeks on the road. Stay tuned for our next exploits.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Croydon, 14th August</title><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/croydon" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Croydon, 14th August" /><published>2021-08-10T05:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-10T05:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://freedomtour.uk/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://freedomtour.uk/croydon">&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Tour is coming to Croydon. More details to be added soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Details of our visit and Crisis Talk in Croydon</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/canva-croydon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/canva-croydon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Southall, 13th August</title><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/southall" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Southall, 13th August" /><published>2021-08-10T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-10T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://freedomtour.uk/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://freedomtour.uk/southall">&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Tour is coming to Southall. More details to be added soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Details of our visit and Crisis Talk in Southall</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/canva-southall.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/canva-southall.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Weymouth, 9-10th August</title><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/weymouth" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weymouth, 9-10th August" /><published>2021-08-09T06:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-09T06:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://freedomtour.uk/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://freedomtour.uk/weymouth">&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Tour is in Weymouth. Below are our plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;today-6pm---the-crisis-talk&quot;&gt;Today, 6pm - The Crisis Talk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;freedomtour.uk/crisis-talk&quot;&gt;Crisis Talk&lt;/a&gt; will take place at &lt;strong&gt;Weymouth Beach&lt;/strong&gt;. Everybody welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are holding a space where people can learn about local campaigns that are shaping different spaces and services in Weymouth. Everyone who attends is invited to be in a discussion group that will feedback its conclusions to the wider assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/675371890524016&quot;&gt;Facebook event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;campaigns-we-hope-to-hear-from-at-the-crisis-talk&quot;&gt;Campaigns we hope to hear from at the Crisis Talk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STEPS, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weyforward.net/&quot;&gt;Weyforward&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wadt.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Weymouth Area Development Trust&lt;/a&gt;, Young People Engage Positive Change, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insulatebritain.com/&quot;&gt;Insulate Britain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/xrdorchesterweymouthportland/&quot;&gt;Extinction Rebellion Dorchester, Weymouth &amp;amp; Portland&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think someone should be telling their story at the event, email freedomtour21@gmail.com or message us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/freedomtour21&quot;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;monday&quot;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pxl_20210809_101548142.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of our conversations is for us to learn from those we speak to, exchange new viewpoints and paradigms, and ultimately invite people to the &lt;a href=&quot;freedomtour.uk/crisis-talk&quot;&gt;Crisis Talk&lt;/a&gt; at 6pm on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all the locals that are helping out. Special thanks to Laura Baldwin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pxl_20210809_103128529.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;press-coverage&quot;&gt;Press Coverage&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few publications decided to write something about our visit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dorset Eye - &lt;a href=&quot;https://dorseteye.com/freedom-tour-arrives-in-weymouth-for-crisis-talks/&quot;&gt;‘Freedom Tour’ arrives in Weymouth for Crisis Talks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dorset Echo - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dorsetecho.co.uk/news/19501304.crisis-talk-weymouth-beach-calling-action-poverty-climate-change/&quot;&gt;‘Crisis talk’ on Weymouth Beach calling for action on poverty and climate change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planet Radio - &lt;a href=&quot;https://planetradio.co.uk/greatest-hits/dorset/news/campaigners-in-weymouth-for-crisis-talk/&quot;&gt;What’s next? Campaigners in Weymouth for ‘Crisis Talk’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also were fortunate enough to be shared on a local Facebook page. All publicity is good publicity, they say!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/facebook.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tuesday&quot;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are speaking to people around the high street, send us a message on instagram (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/freedomtour21/&quot;&gt;@freedomtour21&lt;/a&gt;) if you want to find us and say “Hi”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Details of our visit and Crisis Talk in Weymouth</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/canva-weym2.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/canva-weym2.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Talking Ourselves Into Freedom</title><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/talking-ourselves-into-freedom" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Talking Ourselves Into Freedom" /><published>2021-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://freedomtour.uk/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://freedomtour.uk/talking-ourselves-into-freedom">&lt;p&gt;This Freedom Tour doesn’t have anything to do with the anti-lockdown Freedom Marches. Wouldn’t it be easier to call ourselves something else? Avoid the confusion? Maybe. But there’s something about freedom that is essential to this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep coming back to Nina Simone’s description of it as “no fear”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember it now because in the same &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Si5uW6cnyG4&amp;amp;ab_channel=NinaSimone&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; she describes how “everybody is half dead”, how “everybody avoids everybody, all over the place, in most situations, all of the time.” Doing what we’re doing, approaching people at random on the street, Nina’s words could be our own. People do backflips to avoid you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it makes total sense. After a lifetime of being treated as a prospective consumer to be solicited, a resource to be mined, in this world which will take everything you have if you don’t protect yourself, what can we expect?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what makes one of the deepest joys of this tour when, upon stopping a stranger on the street, you’re able to convince them that genuinely -no really, I’m not kidding- we just want to hear how things are going for you at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some never believe it. They want to know exactly what our aims are, they want to know now, and they stomp off when I explain that we don’t really know yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many can believe it though. And once they do, their bodies change visibly. They relax open, become a little more energetic, and a little more alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we get to share it all, our hopes, dreams, fears, loneliness, fatigue, exasperation, and always deep, deep perseverance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why this other line from Nina’s interview rings out to me now as a kind of credo: “all I’m trying to do all the time is open people up so they can feel themselves and let themselves be open to somebody else.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe this is our aim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;finding-freedom-together&quot;&gt;Finding Freedom Together&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, what’s happening after weeks of talking to hundreds of people is the anxiety of speaking to a stranger is disappearing. We’re finding Nina’s kind of freedom out here; in the town squares, in the parks, in front of the shopping centers, we’re finding a kind of fearlessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this freedom isn’t something we can find alone. Freedom, like fearlessness, is a shared thing. If we can really connect with someone, they’ll lose a little of their fear of the stranger in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freedom is a kind of power that can only be found together and which has a deep longing to be shared. After our Crisis Talk, one of our hosts in Bradford found herself stopping on the walk home and striking up a conversation with strangers in a pub. Something she’d never normally do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for a project which ultimately wants to contribute to a deep systemic transformation of this country and this planet, what does any of this mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-1-to-collective-power-talk&quot;&gt;Step 1 to Collective Power: Talk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s important to remember how conversations have been an essential element of previous moments of mass social change. This is the point the Rob Hopkins beautifully argues toward the end of &lt;em&gt;From What Is to What If&lt;/em&gt; referencing that wild, wild moment of May 1968&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He quotes historian Mark Kurlansky who says, “ask anyone in Paris with fond memories of the spring of 1968, and that is what they will say. People talked.… Students on the street found themselves in conversation with teachers and professors for the first time. For the first time in this rigid, formal, nineteenth-century society, everyone was talking to everyone. ‘Talk to your neighbour’ were words written on the walls.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he quotes an English student in Paris at the time who saw how “those who had never dared say anything before suddenly felt their thoughts to be the most important thing in the world and said so. The helpless and isolated suddenly discovered that collective power lay in their hands. People just went up and talked to one another without a trace of self-consciousness.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who can know which way the causality lies? Maybe this kind of mass talking is an outcome of wider movements, maybe it’s a cause. I suspect though that it is intimately wrapped up as both and that if revolutionary change is some kind of vehicle, talking will be the fuel that moves it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this because of the way that talking dissolves fear. And how Srdja Popovic the revolutionary leader who helped topple Slobodan Milošević describes how “all oppression relies on fear in order to be effective”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not living under a dictatorship like Srdja’s. Fear of punishment by the state is very real for some in this country, but for most there are different fears keeping them in line. Not least, fear of the other, a fear of the stranger on the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point here is, that there is a deep and wonderful experience of freedom to be found in breaking this fear -as Nina Simone said “it’s like a new way of seeing”- but that this experience could be just the beginning of something much bigger.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A thought piece from Greg</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://freedomtour.uk/" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://freedomtour.uk/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Plymouth, 6-7th August</title><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/plymouth" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plymouth, 6-7th August" /><published>2021-08-05T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-05T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://freedomtour.uk/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://freedomtour.uk/plymouth">&lt;p&gt;The Freedom Tour had a great time in Plymouth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;friday&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being moved off twice by the council officials of the City for our offensive pavement parking and street stands, we tucked up our van and continued the journey on foot. We walked around the area surrounding the Sundial, finding engaging the good people in conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our smiles and flyers, we asked what people think about crisis and the state of Plymouth within the wider UK and human condition. What gives them hope and what are they wanting to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of our conversations is for us to learn from those we speak to, exchange new viewpoints and paradigms, and ultimately invite people to Saturday’s &lt;a href=&quot;freedomtour.uk/crisis-talk&quot;&gt;Crisis Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;saturday&quot;&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;morning&quot;&gt;Morning&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We played a game to cheer ourselves up after a hellish downpour, nervously looking at the afternoon’s forecast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3pm---the-crisis-talk&quot;&gt;3pm - The Crisis Talk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Crisis Talk took place at Jigsaw Park. We were joined by many friends and strangers to sit down and hash out the big topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jigsaw-park-map.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;campaigns-we-heard-from-at-the-crisis-talk&quot;&gt;Campaigns we heard from at the Crisis Talk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solidarity Federation Plymouth, All Ways Apples, Food Plymouth &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insulatebritain.com/&quot;&gt;Insulate Britain&lt;/a&gt;, Extinction Rebellion Plymouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;outputs-from-the-crisis-talk&quot;&gt;Outputs From The Crisis Talk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the list of suggestions we got from the Crisis Talk in response to the question “What actions can we as a group take to change the political structures [in order to respond to crises]?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/img-20210809-wa0004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We will try and add more detail about these responses at a later point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;letting-off-some-steam&quot;&gt;Letting Off Some Steam&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we closed the Crisis Talk by having the group paint on our van. we went and had a dance at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visitplymouth.co.uk/whats-on/ocean-city-blues-n-jazz-festival-p2034293&quot;&gt;Blues and Jazz Festival &lt;/a&gt;at the Waterfront before having a walk around the Hoe and swim in the sea. All in a good day’s work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pxl_20210807_202411016.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Details of our visit and Crisis Talk in Plymouth</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/canva-plym-jigsaw.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/canva-plym-jigsaw.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Our time in Taunton</title><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/news/2021/08/04/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our time in Taunton" /><published>2021-08-04T20:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-04T20:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://freedomtour.uk/news/2021/08/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://freedomtour.uk/news/2021/08/04/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-can-any-group-of-people-get-done-in-a-day&quot;&gt;How much can any group of people get done in a day?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the question we sought to investigate with a day in Taunton starting our street approaches at 10 am and directing people to a talk only 5 and a half hours later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our experience early on was a big knockback. The proverbial doors felt slapped in our faces, where some people aggressively wanted to avoid us. I don’t know if they mistakenly believe we are associated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hopenothate.org.uk/2020/08/28/the-uks-emerging-conspiracy-theory-street-movements/&quot;&gt;other groups with names that include the word “Freedom”&lt;/a&gt;, or if there is an endemic air of mistrust of any stranger who might want to offer a different hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, after warming up we managed some powerful conversations and blew out the cobwebs that had gathered during our few days off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;old-dogs-new-tricks&quot;&gt;Old dogs: New tricks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankie gave herself a new spin on the day. She specifically spoke to people about the climate and civil disobedience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She met an 81-year-old who was perturbed by the climate but didn’t know what to do. He was worried about the future of his granddaughters. They had a long conversation that seemed much needed for him, and maybe for all of us. Despite age often being perceived as a barrier in our society, when the conversation turned to civil disobedience, it became clear that it was a strength and allowed him to act in a place of courage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-pied-pipestress-of-taunton&quot;&gt;The Pied Pipestress of Taunton&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The award for most people engaged in one conversation was won by Katie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/img-20210805-wa0019.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these teenagers had met through Pride, aged 13-19. When asked what was important to them, pretty much everything came up. A future politics student explained that they had no choice except to be political when being constantly marginalised. Another told of being deliberately misgendered at school by staff, and the school structure dictating that all students could only be referred to by their registered names, rather than chosen names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These experiences fuelled their determination to act against the discrimination pf this unwelcoming world. Their LGBT education at school was massively lacking and commonly mistake-laden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being in a conversation with Katie was validating for them, given they are continuously invalidated by adults around them. Currently, as legal children, they don’t have much choice over who they can spend time and associate with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fight for them is to be recognised as they are. Their struggle had sharpened their attention for injustice and oppression for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-what-happened-at-the-crisis-talk&quot;&gt;But what happened at the Crisis Talk?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We split up into 3 groups answering two main questions: “What is the issue that you care enough about to do something?! and “What is your practical next step to further this cause?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we like the idea behind these questions, we won’t be asking them again as they were individualistic in nature, when we are aiming for groups to build conclusions that they can share with the assembly and a group can act on in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to Greg plus guest-facilitator Fran for getting the assembly up to speed and holding the space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pxl_20210804_150932383.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, the assembly stayed to eat a homemade no-egg potato salad, plus a mixed-bean salad and some donated brownies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus a cat tried to join the crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/img-20210804-wa0015.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two women and a black and white cat.&quot; title=&quot;Frankie and Katie with a local cat.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Looking back at our first attempt of a single-day trip. In Taunton we started canvassing in the morning for a Crisis Talk the same afternoon.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/pxl_20210804_093532674.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/pxl_20210804_093532674.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bringing your Call-To-Action</title><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/campaign" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bringing your Call-To-Action" /><published>2021-08-03T21:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-03T21:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://freedomtour.uk/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://freedomtour.uk/campaign">&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-can-bring-a-call-to-action&quot;&gt;Who can bring a Call-To-Action?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are reaching out to &lt;strong&gt;groups and campaigns&lt;/strong&gt; that have highlighted crises or issues, and are taking direct action to target the root of these problems, or building community power and cohesion for more caring and resilient communities. We want them to attend a Crisis Talk that we have organised. [See: &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedomtour.uk/crisis-talk&quot;&gt;Detailed Description of Crisis Talk&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-bring-your-call-to-action&quot;&gt;Why bring your Call-To-Action?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons, but here are the big ones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show shared humanity&lt;/strong&gt; in your struggle - people are sharing a bite to eat and a 30-minute chat, this leads one to put value in the concerns of other campaigns even if they don’t directly affect you. This can shift someone from being ignorant or unmoved to a position of support for your cause. [See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/david_fleischer_how_to_fight_prejudice_through_policy_conversations&quot; title=&quot;Deep Canvassing TED Talk&quot;&gt;Deep Canvassing&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educate people that are hard to reach&lt;/strong&gt; - the Crisis Talk is inclusive in a way that exposes many non-progressive or radical people to your campaign and those that they wouldn’t otherwise meet. This is a rare space where certain worlds to collide in a constructive way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recruiting for a campaign&lt;/strong&gt; - You could grow your campaign! Some attendees sign up to a mailing list of a campaign or offer up time as a volunteer/activist. This may be a totally new world for them and their first taste of activism. Be gentle!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-does-this-fit-in-the-crisis-talk&quot;&gt;Where does this fit in the Crisis Talk?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduction/input - Setting the space, ground rules, inviting attendees to testify.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deliberation - 30 mins in groups engaging with one or more questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feedback/Harvest - The main points from each of the groups are returned to the wider assembly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call-to-action stories - Campaign groups tell the assembly about the crisis they are facing and responding to.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All attendees will naturally talk about their crises in the deliberation phase, but the &lt;strong&gt;4th phase&lt;/strong&gt; is a time where pre-selected campaign speakers have a &lt;strong&gt;5-10 minute slot&lt;/strong&gt; telling the whole group about the crises they face and what can be done about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/campaigns-on-van.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of our previous attendees and visiting campaigns have tagged our van.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previous-call-to-actions&quot;&gt;Previous Call-To-Actions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all those who spoke at previous Crisis Talks, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;freedom-tour&quot;&gt;Freedom Tour&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This summer, the Freedom Tour’s happening. It’s a campaign travelling through the UK, aiming to connect and grow the wider movement for a democratic, ecological and sane society. It achieves this through street canvassing and hosting “Crisis Talk” community events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Yes we want people to join us on our own call-to-action!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://freedomtour.uk/&quot; title=&quot;https://freedomtour.uk/&quot;&gt;https://freedomtour.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;abolish-detention&quot;&gt;Abolish Detention&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of individuals that stand against detention for anyone, anywhere. We are outraged at the use of detention centres in the UK. This group focusses on the planned opening of a detention centre in Consett, and how we can combat its opening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Abolish-Detention-Hassockfield-103117778532701/&quot; title=&quot;Abolish Detention - Hassockfield Facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;insulate-britain&quot;&gt;Insulate Britain&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A campaign to pressure the UK Government to reduce home heating emissions to zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.insulatebritain.com/&quot; title=&quot;http://www.insulatebritain.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.insulatebritain.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/insulatebritain&quot; title=&quot;Insulate Britain Facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;extinction-rebellion&quot;&gt;Extinction Rebellion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extinction Rebellion is an international movement that uses non-violent civil disobedience in an attempt to halt mass extinction and minimise the risk of social collapse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://extinctionrebellion.uk/&quot; title=&quot;https://extinctionrebellion.uk/&quot;&gt;https://extinctionrebellion.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Crisis Talk" /><summary type="html">A description of how groups can benefit from coming to the Crisis Talk and presenting their story.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/van2.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/van2.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What is a “Crisis Talk”?</title><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/crisis-talk" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is a “Crisis Talk”?" /><published>2021-07-26T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://freedomtour.uk/crisis-talk</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://freedomtour.uk/crisis-talk">&lt;p&gt;As we are travelling around, we &lt;strong&gt;aim to foster dialogue&lt;/strong&gt;. We want to listen and learn, as much as we want to talk and teach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crisis Talk (Noun)&lt;/strong&gt; - a cross-community event exposing the impact of current crises on a group and asking what actions they can take to improve their resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that the answers to our problems are in all of us, because the answers are very human and can be found in our lived experience. We wish to avoid polarisation and division.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Crisis Talk&lt;/strong&gt; helps us to bring people to the table, asking them to share which of the intersecting crises is impinging on them and what it would mean for them to be able to make headway into challenging their crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happens&quot;&gt;What Happens?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a rough outline of the steps we try to go through… but it is quite an organic, unique thing each time a Crisis Talk happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;before-the-event-we-put-in-the-groundwork&quot;&gt;Before the event, we put in the groundwork:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Researching&lt;/strong&gt; the local circumstances and active local organisations, plus &lt;strong&gt;finding a suitable event location&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inviting groups that are also engaged in a struggle to the event.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Most importantly) &lt;strong&gt;Conversing with strangers&lt;/strong&gt; on the street, hearing their take on The World, and &lt;strong&gt;inviting them to the Crisis Talk&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Admin&lt;/strong&gt;: sending reminder texts and emails, creating online event pages, filling out paperwork, e.g. risk assessments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-a-crisis-talk-runs&quot;&gt;How a Crisis Talk runs:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We rock up in our beautiful blue van at the planned time and start &lt;strong&gt;cooking some delicious free food and create a fun atmosphere&lt;/strong&gt;… think music and warm smiles and the slight electric-tingly-feeling that tells you something special is about to happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rock-up.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share the delicious, nutritious food.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People are invited into the space to &lt;strong&gt;testify about what brought them here today&lt;/strong&gt; and compelled them to speak to the group. (Maximum 2 mins for any testimony)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/testimony.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then the group is broken up into smaller circles and introduced to the questions that will be the basis of the &lt;strong&gt;smaller group dialogue&lt;/strong&gt;. Every small group will need:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;a &lt;strong&gt;facilitator&lt;/strong&gt; to keep the group to the topic, help the group meet its purpose of creating some conclusions/outputs, and ensure the time spent speaking and listening is shared within the circle.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;a &lt;strong&gt;note-taker&lt;/strong&gt; to capture the gist of the dialogue and main conclusions/outputs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/groups.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After 30 mins, the groups conclude and each group nominates someone from their group to &lt;strong&gt;feedback their group’s conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;/outputs to the whole Crisis Talk assembly. All the outputs from all the groups are collated on a large piece of paper for everyone to see.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After a break, some campaigns or individuals are invited to &lt;strong&gt;tell their stories of what can be done to face a crisis&lt;/strong&gt;. Everyone who attended can set themselves some next steps or homework of how they can get the World to something closer to that they wish to see.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We finish with some &lt;strong&gt;fun social time and relaxing&lt;/strong&gt; into being with one another. We also invite people to write/draw on our van!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/creative.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-the-freedom-tour-get-out-of-it&quot;&gt;What does the Freedom Tour get out of it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from a social buzz, &lt;strong&gt;warm sense of communit&lt;/strong&gt;y, and the lingering feeling that &lt;strong&gt;something has been set in motion&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it really: we get to be around people in a space created to help each of us be open, connected, supported, empowered, and human. We learn a lot from those we share the space with and we believe some amazing work may happen down the road due to the connections, introductions, and ideas brewed here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope it is as much of a gift to those who take part, as to those who host it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-when-are-you-going-to-host-a-crisis-talk&quot;&gt;So when are YOU going to host a Crisis Talk?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;??You, the reader, can also do this where you are. It can be daunting, but it is also natural and you have it in you to host a Crisis Talk. We can’t be the only ones doing this when the stakes are so high and the process is so fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need advice and guidance, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://freedomtour.uk/join-us/&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When we say we will be holding a &quot;Crisis Talk&quot;, what does that look like and what do we intend to achieve?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/crisis-talk.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/crisis-talk.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A New Route! The Freedom Tour is back on the road</title><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/news/2021/07/05/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A New Route! The Freedom Tour is back on the road" /><published>2021-07-05T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-05T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://freedomtour.uk/news/2021/07/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://freedomtour.uk/news/2021/07/05/">&lt;p&gt;We had to take a brief pause to make sure none of us were carrying Covid-19 and risk spreading it to the places we were visiting, but it’s given us time to hone the schedule and think carefully about where we’re going next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a painful process, as we can’t visit everywhere. But we’re thrilled to be landing in these spots across England and Wales:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/screenshot-2021-07-08-at-12-59-06.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">After a brief Covid-19 induce hiatus, the Freedom Tour is back on the road with a new route.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/screenshot-2021-07-08-at-12-53-16.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/screenshot-2021-07-08-at-12-53-16.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Freedom Tour in Manchester</title><link href="https://freedomtour.uk/news/2021/07/05/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Freedom Tour in Manchester" /><published>2021-07-05T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-05T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://freedomtour.uk/news/2021/07/</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://freedomtour.uk/news/2021/07/05/">&lt;p&gt;After bedding in with our new crew for the week in Wigan we set off to Manchester…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryebank fields is a beautiful wild area enjoyed (and lived in!) by many beings which is under threat of development and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.saveryebankfields.org/&quot;&gt;protection camp&lt;/a&gt; warmly invited us to make our own bubble of a camp, navigating needs and covid safety. Gratitude to the humans taking a stand for the land, plants and creatures that inhabit Ryebank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being in a big city, with so many options to consider, we collectively decided to spend a day in Piccadilly Gardens in the centre, having conversations and culminating in a Crisis Talk - a Big Chat rebranded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were instantly met with challenges that became apparent throughout the day we weren’t alone in experiencing. Street harassment, and the council questioning the validity of our presence in the park with our camp kitchen (apparently you can get fined for feeding the homeless!). This was all handled deftly by our collective, bringing us together and in itself offering new ways of navigating through challenges when they are faced as a community rather than as individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got set up we were in the park for the rest of the day, serving tea, coffee &amp;amp; biscuits and having conversations. Our focus was shifting to the crises we face and what would it take for us to stand in defiance for what we care deeply about. People were engaged and keen to connect to wider movements, with many people signing up to hear more. Our youngest tour member co-held the kitchen fort, pulling together a massive pot of delicious veggie pasta pesto (2 pots actually to encompass some dietary needs!) which we dished out as we got together for the Crisis Talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were up against the intensity of the environment, more groups of folks were beginning to drink around the park and the fountain &amp;amp; general hubbub noise had been going strong all day but a diverse group of people came together to share and listen to what they saw going on in the world around them. The people we met in Manchester talked a lot about how the education system is failing young people. The pressures it’s putting on kids to achieve results and the narrow way it has of defining intelligence is contributing to a mental health crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One guy, who’d described growing up traumatised through the care system, left the assembly saying how good it felt to have a voice. We’ve stayed in touch with him and he’s spreading the word about the Freedom Tour throughout Manchester still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were packed up we blasted out Basement Jaxx Where’s your head at? and boogied out what was left of our energy for the day before heading back to camp for a well-deserved rest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the weekend had us swimming in a glorious lake, chatting to folk at the Ryebank skillshare, some of our members gave a talk on Insulate Britain, and attending talks &amp;amp; music there. whilst some folk headed home, the football didn’t, so we rounded off the night with a street party - shout out to folk that joined us to dance away the defeat!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/whatsapp-image-2021-07-09-at-23-22-43.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://freedomtour.uk/assets/images/whatsapp-image-2021-07-09-at-23-22-43.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>